Guide to the Roger Sherman (1721-1793) Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Roger Sherman (1721-1793) collection
1749-1904
MS 447
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
1
(2 boxes)
Correspondence, reports, legal records, financial documents and genealogical material of Roger Sherman, signer of the Declaration of Independence. Included are both family letters and political correspondence. Of special interest are the letters to Governor Jonathan Trumbull on the relationship of Connecticut to the prosecution of the war (1777-1780). Among Sherman's writings are a report from the Constitutional Convention (1787), a note on the proposal for a national bank (1791) and a printed copy of his Almanac for 1760. Genealogical and other papers assembled by Sherman's grandson, George Frisbie Hoar (1826-1904) are also in the collection. Major correspondents are Oliver Ellsworth, Samuel Hopkins, Titus Hosmer, Samuel Huntington, Stephen Mix Mitchell and William Williams.
Sherman, Roger, 1721-1793
Immediate Source of Acquisition
In part, transferred from the Baldwin Family Papers (MS 55), and gift of Charles, Hugh, and Rockwood Foster and the estate of Frances Hoar Foster.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Biographical / Historical
Roger Sherman was born in 1721 in Newton, Massachusetts, and early moved to Stoughton, Massachusetts, where he attended the public schools and later learned the shoemaker's trade. He moved to New Milford, Connecticut, in 1743 and became surveyor of New Haven County in 1745. During this period Sherman was engaged in the study of law and was admitted to the bar in 1754. He was a member of the Connecticut Assembly in 1755, 1756, 1758-61 and 1764-66. As Justice of the Peace for Litchfield County (1755-1761), he issued the warrant for the arrest of Timothy Hurlburt. He served as judge of the New Haven Superior Court and was a member of the State Senate. He served as Treasurer of Yale College from 1765 to 1776. He was a member of the Continental Congress 1774-1781, 1783, and 1784, and signed the Declaration of Independence as a member of the committee which drafted it. He was also on the committee which drafted the Articles of Confederation, and a delegate to the Constitutional Convention of 1787. As such he became the only person to sign all the great American state papers: the Articles of Association, of 1774, the Declaration of Independence of 1776, the Articles of Confederation in 1783, and the Constitution in 1787.
Scope and Contents
Correspondence, reports, legal records, financial documents and genealogical material of Roger Sherman, signer of the Declaration of Independence. Included are both family letters and political correspondence. Of special interest are the letters to Governor Jonathan Trumbull on the relationship of Connecticut to the prosecution of the war (1777-1780). Among Sherman's writings are a report from the Constitutional Convention (1787), a note on the proposal for a national bank (1791) and a printed copy of his Almanac for 1760. Genealogical and other papers assembled by Sherman's grandson, George Frisbie Hoar (1826-1904) are also in the collection. Major correspondents are Oliver Ellsworth, Samuel Hopkins, Titus Hosmer, Samuel Huntington, Stephen Mix Mitchell and William Williams.
Arrangement
The Papers of Roger Sherman (1721-1793) are divided into two parts. The first consists of about two hundred items which were taken from the Baldwin Family Papers. Included here are correspondence for the years 1783-1793, financial records, and a survey map made by Roger Sherman in 1753. A folder list in this register provides an over-all guide to these materials. In addition, each item is individually catalogued in the Manuscripts and Archives catalogue under the heading, Roger Sherman, 1721-1793.
In 1975 Yale University Library acquired the second part, ninety items, as a gift from Charles H. W. Foster, Hugh K. Foster and Rockwood H. Foster. These comprise correspondence for the period 1770-1790, writings, including notes on the Constitution and on proposals for a national bank, a printed almanac compiled by Sherman in 1760, and materials on the Sherman family. An itemized list of these materials is in this register under the title, ROGER SHERMAN COLLECTION, ADDITION.
Appendix: Persons Mentioned in the Collection (Part I)
Adams, John, Pres. U.S., 1735-1826
Allen, Benjamin
Arnold, Benedict, 1741-1801
Austin, David
Baldwin, Ebenezer, 1790-1837
Baldwin, Simeon, 1761-1851
Barclay, Andrew
Bogert, Rudolph
Brady, James
Butler, Zebulon, 1731-1795
Chauncey, Charles, 1747-1823
Denison, Nathan
Edwards, Pierpont, 1750-1826
Ellsworth, Oliver, 1745-1807
Franklin, John, 1749-1831
Franklin, W.
Gibbs, Henry, 1749-1794
Goodhue, Benjamin, 1748-1814
Gray, Samuel
Guno, Nathan
Hazen, Moses, 1733-1802
Herox, James
Hillhouse, James, 1754-1832
Holmes, Temperance
Howell, Joseph
Humphreys, David, 1752-1818
Huntington, Samuel, 1731-1796
Hurlburt, Timothy
Imlay, William
Johnson, William Samuel, 1727-1819
Lanning, Henry
Leavenworth, Jesse
Leavensworth, I.
Lynde, Joseph
Mallet, Peter
Mason, George, 1725-1792
Mitchell, Justus, 1754-1806
Mix, Jonathan, 1753-1817
Noble, Stephen
North, Charles
Ogden, Robert, 1746-1826
Otis, Samuel Alleyne, 1740-1814
Payne, Col.
Pearson and Glover, firm, New Haven
Prescott, Henry
Safford, Samuel
Sherman, Elizabeth, 1765-1850
Sherman, Elizabeth, 1778-1834
Sherman, Harriet, 1776-1795
Sherman, Isaac, 1753-1819
Sherman, John, 1750-1802
Sherman, Maria, 1774-1857
Sherman, Rebecca (Prescott), 1742-1813
Sherman, Roger, 1721-1793
Sherman, William, 1751-1789
Si1kin, George
Spencer, Joseph
Squiers, Samuel
Strong, aoseph, 1753-1834
Swift, Heman, 1733-1814
Toller, Daniel
Toller, Lazarus
Wales, Nathaniel
Whiting, William Jos.
Whi tman, Mary
Williams, Nathan, 1735-1829
Willis, Roswell
Winched, Azariah
Wooster, David, 1711-1777
Appendix: Persons Mentioned in the Collection (Part II)
Adams, Simon, 1722-1803 7
Ames, Ellis, 1809-1884 33
Boutwell, George Sewall, 1818-1905 32
Butler, Zebulon, 1731-1795 12
Ellery, William, 1727-1820 10
Ellsworth, Oliver, 1745-1807 6,8,16
Gerard, Conrad Alexandre, 1729-1790 6
Griswold, Matthew, 1714-1799 17
Hoar, George Frisbie, 1826-1904 29-33
Hosmer, Titus, 1737-1780 6, 16
Huntington, Samuel, 1731-1796 9
Jameson, John Franklin, 1859-1937 29
Jay, John, 1745-1829 6
Jefferson, Thomas, Pres.U.S., 1743-1826 11
Johnson, William Samuel, 1727-1818 17
Lee, Thomas Sim, 1745-1819 10
Mitchell, Stephen Mix, 1743-1835 17
Osgood, Samuel, 1747/48-1813 10
Sherman, Elizabeth, 1765-1850 1
Sherman, Isaac, 1753-1819 2
Sherman, Nathaniel, 1724-1797 3
Sherman, Rebecca (Prescott), 1742-1813 4
Sherman, William, 1751-1789 15
Stiles, Ezra, 1727-1795 11
Trumbull, Jonathan, 1710-1785 6
Williams, William, 1731-1811 11
Wolcott, Oliver, 1726-1797 17
Law; New England theology; Susquehanna Claim, 1753-1808; Connecticut -- History -- Colonial period, ca. 1600-1775; Constitutional history -- United States; United States -- History -- 1783-1865; United States -- History -- Colonial period, ca. 1600-1775; United States -- History -- Revolution, 1775-1783 -- Finance; United States -- History -- Revolution, 1775-1783 -- Equipment and supplies; United States -- History -- Revolution, 1775-1783; United States -- Politics and government; Almanacs; Lawyers; Legislators; Politicians; Ames, Ellis, 1809-1886; Austin, David, 1759-1831; Baldwin, Simeon, 1761-1851; Butler, Zebulon, 1731-1795; Channing, Henry, 1760?-1840; Denison, Nathan; Ellsworth, Oliver, 1745-1807; Franklin, John, 1749-1831; Gibbs, Henry, 1749-1794; Goodhue, Benjamin, 1748-1814; Hazen, Moses, 1733-1803; Hoar, George Frisbie, 1826-1904; Holmes, Temperance; Hopkins, Samuel, 1721-1803; Hosmer, Titus, 1737-1780; Howell, Joseph (Joseph Williams), 1857-1918; Humphreys, David, 1752-1818; Huntington, Samuel, 1731-1796; Imlay, William, 1742-1807; Johnson, William Samuel, 1727-1819; Lynde, Joseph, 1702-1788; Marsh, Charles, 1765-1849; Mitchell, Justus, 1754-1806; Mitchell, Stephen Mix, 1743-1835; Morris, Gouverneur, 1752-1816; Ogden, Robert, 1746-1826; Otis, Samuel Allyne, 1740-1814; Prescott, Henry; Safford, Samuel; Sherman, Elizabeth, 1765-1850; Sherman, Elizabeth, 1778-1834; Sherman, Harriet, 1776-1795; Sherman, Isaac, 1753-1819; Sherman, Maria, 1774-1857; Sherman, Nathaniel, 1727-1797; Sherman, Rebecca Prescott, 1742-1813; Sherman, Roger, 1721-1793; Sherman, William, 1751-1789; Silkin, George; Spencer, Joseph, 1714-1789; Strong, Joseph, 1753-1834; Swift, Heman, 1733-1814; Whitman, Mary; Williams, Nathan, 1735-1829; Willis, Roswell; Wooster, David, 1711-1777; Sherman family; United States. Constitutional Convention -- 1787; United States. Continental Army; United States. Constitution
- Part I
  - Plan for Partridge Thacher's Land, 1753 February 19 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Invoices, account of Roger Sherman with Ebenezer Storer and Son, 1758 May 15, November 23 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - An Astronomical Diary, or an Almanack, for the Year of Our Lord Jesus Christ, 1760, by Roger Sherman (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Account books (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence
    - 1749-1774 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - 1775-1782 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - 1783 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - 1784 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - 1785-1788 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - 1789 Jan -Jun (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - , typed extracts, 1789 March -1792 March (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - 1789 Ju1 -Dec (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - 1790 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - 1791 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - 1792 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - 1793-1796 (Estate) (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - List of Roger Sherman material in Group 200, Evarts Family Papers (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Part II
  Arrangement
  Arranged in four series: I. CORRESPONDENCE (1770-1790); II. WRITINGS (1760-1794); III. FINANCIAL AND LEGAL DOCUMENTS (1734-1792); and IV. GENEALOGICAL (1855-1904)
  The correspondence is arranged alphabetically by writer. The other materials are arranged chronologically, and each item is fully described in the succeeding pages.
  Scope and Contents
  This addition of about ninety items to the Roger Sherman Collection comprises miscellaneous correspondence of Roger Sherman, writings and notes on the Constitution, on proposals for a national bank, a printed almanac compiled by Sherman in 1760, and materials on the Sherman family. These papers, as well as two family Bibles, were given in 1975 as a gift to Yale University Library by Charles H.W. Foster, Hugh Foster and Rockwood Foster. Because the collection includes not only papers contemporary with Roger Sherman, but also family letters and genealogical materials dating from the 19th and 20th centuries, the items have been arranged both by period and kind into four series.
  - CORRESPONDENCE, 1770-1790; 1
    - Part A. Roger Sherman's Correspondence
      - Sherman, Elizabeth (1765-1850) (Box 2, Folder 1)
        ALS to her father, Roger Sherman, at New York, announcing her brother William's death. 1789 Jun 29, New Haven. [4] p. with address on outside wrapper.
      - Sherman, Isaac (1753-1819) (Box 2, Folder 2)
        ALS to his father, Roger Sherman, at Philadelphia about his enlistment in the army and his station at Brookline. "We have no certain News from the British Troops ...The People in Boston have been and are still in a very disagreeable situation." 1775 Sep 8, Brookline Fort at Sewa11s Point. [2] p. with address and seal on verso. Copy in another hand.
      - Sherman, Nathaniel (1724-1797) (Box 2, Folder 3)
        ALS to his brother, Roger Sherman, at New York, asking his advice on exchanging Continental Securities for State Notes. 1789 Mar 14, East Windsor. [3] p. with address and seal on verso.
      - Sherman, Roger (Box 2, Folder 4)
        ALS to his wife, Rebecca, on her birthday. [n.p.]. Fragment, inlaid.
      - Sherman, Roger (Box 2, Folder 5)
        ALS to unidentified correspondenct about the price of a stocking 100m. References also to the Congress, and reports of Boston being fired on. 1774 Sep 9, Philadelphia. 1 p. mounted
      - Sherman, Roger, Samuel Huntington (1731-1796), and Titus Hosmer (1737-1780) (Box 2, Folder 6)
        ALS to Governor Jonathan Trumbull (1710-1785) in Connecticut on sending Ammunition, on the evacuation of Ticonderoga, and listing the expected representatives to the Convention from Massachusetts, New Hampshire, Rhode Island and New York. 1777 Aug 1, Springfield. [2] p. folio, mended.
      - Sherman, Roger (Box 2, Folder 6)
        ALS to Governor Jonathan Trumbull on finances, on the debate over the relation of the states to the United States, and whether troops serving in the war should be rewarded with land. 1778 Oct 15, Philadelphia. [2] p. folio. Signature pasted on.
      - Sherman, Roger, and Oliver Ellsworth (1745-1807) (Box 2, Folder 6)
        ALS to Governor Jonathan Trumbull-on the appointment of Colonel Joseph Trumbull, and on the financial questions under consideration by the Congress. 1778 Nov 10, Philadelphia. [3] p. Note of receipt on verso.
      - Sherman, Roger, and Oliver Ellsworth (Box 2, Folder 6)
        ALS to Governor Jonathan Trumbull on the question of limiting prices, under consideration by Congress. "We hope that some measures will soon be adopted for introducing a stable medium of Trade that will render a limitation of prices unnessary [sic]." Also reporting on the difficult departure of [John] Jay and [Conrad Alexandre] Gerard for France. 1780 Feb 15, Philadelphia. 1 p. address on versov
      - Sherman, Roger (Box 2, Folder 7)
        ALS to Major [Simon] Adams (1722-1803) with accounts of "an action on Rhode Island," the French fleet in Boston, and asking for news of "what has been done in Congress since I left it." 1778 Sep 1, White Plains. 1 p.
      - Sherman, Roger (Box 2, Folder 8)
        ALS to Oliver Ellsworth at Philadelphia on the circulation of money and on finances in Connecticut. 1780 Apr 27, New Haven. [2] p.
      - Sherman, Roger (Box 2, Folder 9)
        ALS to Samuel Huntington at New Haven with news of the business before Congress: admission of Vermont to the Union; letters from Spain; the arrival of the French fleet. 1781 Aug 20, Philadelphia. 1 p. with address and seal on verso.
      - Sherman, Roger (Box 2, Folder 10)
        ALS to unidentified member of the Connecticut House of Representatives discussing the question of Congress' authority to award half-pay for life to officers of the army. 1784 Mar ,Annapolis. [3] p. Signature pasted on. The names of Messrs. Osgood, Lee and Ellery recorded in Sherman's hand as members of the Conunittee. Address on verso.
      - Sherman, Roger (Box 2, Folder 11)
        ALS to William Williams (1731-1811) with news on the attitudes of the various states to "the impost recommended by Congress," other financial matters and a discussion on "the western territory." 1784 May 4, Annapolis. [3] p.
      - Sherman, Roger (Box 2, Folder 11)
        ALS to Ezra Stiles at New Haven introducing Thomas Jefferson "...now on his way to Boston, there to embark for Europe, he wishes to gain what acquaintance he can with the country as he passes through. He is a Gentleman, of much Philosophical as wlas political knowledge..." 1784 May 11, Annapolis. 1 p. with address and seal on outer page.
      - Sherman, Roger (Box 2, Folder 12)
        ALS to Zebulon Butler (1731-1795) in Wyoming, [no state], on the claims of the people settled in Pennsylvania 1Iunder the claim of Connecticut ... it will be for the interest of all of them to get a confirmation of their title. II 1787 Sep 13, Philadelphia. 1 p. with signature pasted on. Address on outer page.
      - Sherman, Roger (Box 2, Folder 13)
        ALS to Samuel Hopkins:, (1721-1803), discussing Hopkins' book, An Inquiry into the Nature of True Holiness (1773). Sherman defends "self-love" and questions Hopkins' proposition "that it is the duty of a person to be willing to give up his eternal interest for the Glory of God." 1790 Jun 28, New York. [6] p. and cover sheet marked, "Copy of a letter to the Revd. S. Hopkins June 1790."
      - Hopkins, Samuel (Box 2, Folder 13)
        ALS to Roger Sherman, defending his views, declaring that self-love "can answer no good end,: and offering the idea of "universal benevolence" in its place. 1790 Aug 2, Newport. 15 p. in paper covers.
      - Sherman, Roger (Box 2, Folder 13)
        ALS to Samuel Hopkins replying to his letter of 1790 Aug 2, suggesting that Hopkins uses "the term selflove in a narrower sense than it is used in general by others." Sherman maintains that "our own temporal as well as spiritual good may be lawfully sought and enjoyed and our sensitive appetites gratified, so that it not be done in a manner or degree prohibited by law." 1790 October, [7] p. with verso of outer sheet marked "Copy of a Letter to the Revd. S. Hopkins. October 1790." Sewed together with letter of 1790 Jun 28.
      - Sherman, Roger, 14 (Box 2, Folder 14)
        AL to Jedediah Morse (1761-1826) at Charleston near Boston, commenting on and correcting Morse's history of Connecticut. 1792 Feb 11, Philadelphia. [2] p. no signature. Note on verso of last leaf, "Substance of a Letter to Revd. Jed. Morse." Wrapper with address, traces of seal, and note apologizing for the "roughness and inaccuracy of the foregoing letter."
      - Sherman, William (1751-1789), 15 (Box 2, Folder 15)
        ALS to his father, Roger Sherman, at New Haven on his journey to Fort Penn. "Two days before I arrived at Fort Penn Indians had killed one boy, one horse and speared two others ..." He also discusses his possibilities for settling in the region, and its appearance. 1782 June 10, Wyoming,[no state]. 1 p. with address on verso.
    - Part B. Correspondence of Others
      - Hosmer, Titus (1737-1780) (Box 2, Folder 16)
        ALS to Oliver Ellsworth (1748-1808) asking him to take his "Seat in Congress as soon as you can. Mr. Sherman leaves us next day after tomorrow to go to the Army & Home." 1778 Aug 11, Philadelphia. 1 p.
      - S?, I (Box 2, Folder 17)
        ALS to General [Oliver] Wolcott" (1726-1797) on the conduct of the war mentioning, among others, General Hart's Brigade, the rotation of troops, news of the "Tory fleet," the situations at New York and Newport, and the reca1 of Generals [Henry] Clinton and [William] Tryon to England. 1779 Aug 10, Lebanon [no state]. [4] p.
      - Mitchell, Stephen Mix (1743-1835), and William Samuel Johnson (1727-1819) (Box 2, Folder 17)
        ALS to Governor [Matthew] Griswold (1714-1799) reporting on their inability to bring forward the report of the Comittee on the western territory, on the reorganization of the department of government, on Indian treaties, trade relations with Britain. "We still hope that before tis too late America will arouze from her Lethargy, remember her first, her reciproca1 Love, & set her foes of every Description: at 'scornful Defiance, which she is abundantly able to do, if she wisely makes use of the means in her power." 1786 Apr 12, New York. [4] p. Note at end: "Copy of our Letter to Governor Griswold April 12, 1786."
  - WRITINGS, 1760-1794; 2
    - An astronomical diary or almanack for the year of-our Lord Christ, 1760 (Box 2, Folder 18)
      Boston, 1760. [24] p. (See also another, larger, copy in Beinecke.)
    - MS record, of information by James Dean on false provision bills made up by Walter Livingstone for the Commissary in the northern department for the use of the army. (Box 2, Folder 19)
      Record in the hand of Roger Sherman, marked, "James Dean's Information." Philadelphia. [2] p.
    - MS, "Report of the Committee of the Whole House" (Box 2, Folder 20)
      consisting of an outline of 19 numbered paragraphs of the proposed government structure. "Resolved, That it is the opinion of this Committee that the government of the U.S. ought to consist of a Supreme legislative, Judiciary & Executive.", [n.p.]. [5] p. with a marginal note by Sherman: "Connecticut has added 21,140,000 acres to" the Union none of which the King of Gr. Britain had right to grant."
    - MS, notes on the debate on the national bank. [n. p. ]. 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 21)
      Note in another hand: "This handed to J.M. by Mr. Sherman, during the debate on the constitutionality of the Bill for a National Bank... "
    - [Memorabilia]. Flyleaf and printed page from an unidentified book. (Box 2, Folder 22)
      Blank page signed: "Roger Sherman, Sarah Sherman's 1794." Printed leaf with a poem titled, "To my brother the author," by Edward Heylyn, I.C.
  - FINANCIAL AND LEGAL DOCUMENTS, 1734-1792; 3
    - AD, Plat [of William Sherman's land]. (Box 2, Folder 23)
      "Drawn by the scale of ten of Mr. Ganters Chains in an inch by Ebenezer Woodward, Junior, Surveyor. A True Copy Examined by Benjamin Rolfe... " [n.d.] 37x30 em. (For description of this land, see also articles from the Massapoag Journal, 1855, in folder 33.)
    - ADS, 5 miscellaneous receipts for goods delivered to and paid for by Roger Sherman, 1764-1766; one receipt for money received by Roger Sherman, et. al., 1782; 2 itemized book bills, 1767. (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Legal documents, 1754-1786
      - Roger Sherman and Israel Baldwin. Record of a survey of land in New Milford., 1754 February 18 (Box 2, Folder 25)
      - Roger Sherman and Daniel Bostwick. Record of a survey of land in New Milford., 1754 February 18 (Box 2, Folder 25)
      - Signature: "R. Sherman Just. Quorum" on a fragment, Litchfield., 1761 January 4 (Box 2, Folder 25)
      - ADS by Roger Sherman. A complaint of a felony against "one Joel Taylor.", 1758 April 18 (Box 2, Folder 25)
        Countersigned by Samuel Olmstead and James Lockwood, Justices of the Peace., Norwalk. [2] p. With note: "the above written is a True Copy of Record Examined [by] me James Lockwood Justice of Peace."
      - AD, recording the sale of land in New Milford by Isaac Buck to Solomon Palmer, 1758 December 29 (Box 2, Folder 25)
        Countersigned by Roger Sherman as Justice of the Peace.
      - AD, recording the sale of land in New Milford by Isaac Moss to James Bradshaw, 1761 March 25 (Box 2, Folder 25)
      - ADS pay order for Barnabas Dean, Hartford, 1777 September 4 (Box 2, Folder 25)
      - DS (printed forms filled in), three summonses signed by Roger Sherman. 1775 Dec 21, New Haven; 1776 Mar 14, New Haven; 1788 Mar 17, New Haven, 1775-1788 (Box 2, Folder 25)
      - ADS, memorial to the General Assembly of the State of Connecticut for permission to convert 104.l0 (British) in bills of credit into hard money, Hartford? [3]p., 1783 January [undated] (Box 2, Folder 25)
        With two notes: "In the upper House the Prayer of this Memorial is granted... (signed) George Wyllys." "dissented to in the lower house (signed) S[tephen] M[ix] Mitchell, Clerk."
      - AD, opinion in the case of Timothy Hinman VB. Benjamin Stiles, February term, Litchfield County Superior Court. No signature., 1786 (Box 2, Folder 25)
        0
      - Sherman, John. Ledger., 1792 April 14 (Box 2, Folder 26)
        "An account of final settlement of certificates ...to the officers and soldiers of the Connecticut line of the late Continental army.". Countersigned by Joseph Howell for the Pay Office and transmitted to Roger Sherman. Folio [16] p.
      - DS, Ahauton, &c to Wentworth &c, Libro 49 Folio 172. (Box 2, Folder 26A)
        Indenture (typed copy) for land in the township of Stoughton bought by John Wentworth and William Sherman from Amos Ahauton, Thomas Ahauton, Simon George, Hezekiah Squamoag and George Hunter, resident of the Indian plantation Punkapoag. Original entered October 14, 1734 in the Records of Deeds from the County of Suffolk, Massachusetts, Libra 19 Folio 172. Attested as "a true copy" by F. Semple, Registrar, [no date]. For map of this property, see "Plat- of William Sherman's land," folder 23.
      - DS, Sherman to Badlam, Libra 67 Folio 212. (Box 2, Folder 26A)